Where do those scars lie within your chest?
sono kizu wa mune no doko ni arimasu ka?
Can you hear my voice somewhere inside your heart?
kono koe wa kokoro no dokoka de kikoeteimasu ka?
When your scars and mine join together...
sono kizu to kono kizu wo kasaneta nara
When my voice and yours resound together...
kono koe to sono koe wo hibikaseta nara
Our intensity, hot tears, and bashful smiles...
hageshisa atsui namida hazukashisou na hohoemi
I used to think nothing of them, but now,
anna ni mo nanimo nai tte omoeteta watashi kara
So many unstoppable feelings are overflowing!
afuredasu yo konna ni mo tomedo nai kanjou ga ima
You're the one who finds yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo mitsukedasu
You're the one who saves yourself.
kimi ga kimi wo sukuidasu
So much is wrong and everyone breaks into a run.
machigai darake de daremo ga hashiridasu
You're the one who lives your own life,
kimi ga kimi wo ikite yuku
Trembling, hesitating all the while
furue nagara, tomadoi nagara
In a world where you're never truly alone.
hitori kiri janai sekai
But you're the only one of you there is!
dakedo kimi wa tatta ichi nin kimi shika inai
（チセ）ハア…
（チセ）は〜い
Coming.
Morning, Chise!
（ステラ）おはよ チセ
（チセ）ステラ…
Stella.
What's wrong? You look shocked.
（ステラ）
どうしたの？ びっくりした顔して
Er, I didn't think you'd actually come by.
（チセ）えっと…
本当に来てくれると思わなくて
I'm not a liar.
私 うそつきじゃないわよ
I-It must be cold. Come in.
さ… 寒いでしょ　入って
Thanks.
ありがとう
（チセ）うわあ… すごいね
Wow, this is amazing.
You made all this?
これ全部 ステラが？
I-It's not a big deal.
た… 大したことないわよ
契約だったし
It was our contract.
Are you sure you should be wandering out by yourself?
（エリアス）
いいのかい？
１人で出歩いたりして
No one's going to abduct me right after Christmas.
クリスマス明けに
人さらいなんて出ないわよ
You were abducted on Christmas, though.
（エリアス）
君たちはクリスマスに
人さらいにあったけどね
（ステラ）やめてよ！ もう〜
Stop it!
Jeez.
I thought a mage's home
would have a more ominous vibe.
魔法使いの家って
も〜っと おどろおどろしいのかと
思ってたけど
But it's spacious and clean.
広くて きれいね
Y-Yeah.
I guess I shouldn't tell her
there's all kinds of creatures on her.
（チセ）
いろいろ乗ってるのは
言わないほうがいいかな
I'll be in my study.
（エリアス）
僕は書斎にいるから
好きにして大丈夫だよ
You can enjoy yourselves.
はい
Okay.
Ah, um...
あ〜 えっと…
Want to come to my room?
私の部屋に行く？
いいの？
Really?
（ステラ）わあ！
I smell herbs.
ハーブの匂いがする
When are you going back to London?
（チセ）いつ ロンドンに？
Tonight.
（ステラ）今夜
また来月 遊びに来るから
うちにも来てね
I'll come hang out again next month,
so you come to my place, too.
Okay.
This is good.
（ステラ）おいしい！
Do you want to take some with you?
（チセ）よかったら 持っていく？
Really? Thanks!
（ステラ）ホント？ うれしい！
In return for the snacks.
（チセ）お菓子のお礼
A return for a return... It's gonna
be Christmas every time we meet.
お礼にお礼で
会う度 クリスマスになっちゃうわ
Say, Stella,
あの… ステラ
it's been a long time since I've made a friend.
私 友達が出来たのが久しぶりで
どうしたらいいのか…
I don't know what to do.
その…
It'd help if you could tell me.
教えてくれると すごく助かる
（ステラ）アハハ！
Invite me to do whatever you want to do,
自分のやりたいことに誘えばいいし
話せばいいのに
and just talk with me.
What if they don't like it, though?
でも その人が嫌がったら…
You're obviously not the same person as your friend.
相手と自分が違うのは当たり前
You're obviously not gonna have all the same interests.
やりたいことが違うのも当たり前
分かり合うためじゃなくて
話し合うために言葉はあるのよ
Words aren't for understanding each other.
They exist for the sake of talking to each other.
Or so my Dad says, but honestly,
a jerk is a jerk from beginning to end.
て… よく パパが言ってるけど
ムカつく相手は
最初から最後までムカつくわよね
You're so mature, Stella.
（チセ）
ステラは すごく大人なんだね
Even though you're about my age.
私と同じくらいなのに
I hope so.
（ステラ）だといいけど
そういえば いくつ？
Oh yeah, how old are you again?
10歳よ
I'm ten.
（チセ）ん？
（ステラ）10歳
Hm?
Ten.
Ten...
10歳…
How about you?
（ステラ）チセは？
Almost sixteen.
もうすぐ16
I'd decided I would say what I
mean to say, but it's pretty hard.
言いたいことは ちゃんと言うって
決めたんだけど
なかなか うまくできなくて
Let's practice, then.
じゃあ 練習ね
Practice?
練習…
You can't be selfish, though.
（ステラ）でも わがままはダメよ
チセは
そういうの言わなそうだけど
Although you don't seem like you would be.
I'm really selfish.
私は すごくわがままだよ
早くステラの家に
遊びに行けたらいいなって思ってる
I'm hoping to come over to your place soon.
That's not practice, though.
（ステラ）
それじゃ 練習にならないわ
That's just a plan.
予定だもん それ
Elias...
（チセ）エリアス？
（ステラ）え？
Silky, did he leave a note?
（チセ）
シルキー 書き置きはある？
（ステラ）どこ行くの？
Where are you going?
Sorry, Ruth, can you walk Stella home?
ごめん ルツ
ステラを送ってもらっていい？
Yeah, are you going after him?
追いかけるのか？
Yeah.
うん ちょっとね
（ルツ）ハア…
You're both strangely dishonest.
お前も あいつも
変に素直じゃない
Sorry, Stella. Let's hang out again sometime.
ごめんね ステラ
また遊ぼうね
What's up with her?
何なのよ…
"Say what she means to say"...
（ルツ）“言いたいことを言え”
She talks more with her arms
and legs than with her mouth.
あいつは口より 手や足のほうが
おしゃべりなんだ
（チセ）
ダメだ どんどん離されていく
It's no use. He keeps getting further.
What's gotten into him?
どうしたんだろう
ハア… ハア…
（チセ）
やるべきことをやるための姿に
I'll take on the form I need to
take to do what needs to be done.
キツネの足じゃ遅すぎる
I can't keep up with the legs of a fox.
I'd be too big with the body of a bear.
熊の体じゃ大きすぎる
I have to run faster.
もっと速く走らなきゃ
I have to run further.
もっと長く走れなきゃ
I have to catch him.
捕まえなきゃ
これが… 私の望みだ
This is my wish.
Hey, did you hear something?
なあ 何か聞こえないか？
オオカミみてえな
It sounded like a wolf.
Probably a dog.
（男性Ｂ）犬だろ
Maybe it's looking for its pack or something.
仲間でも探してんのかね
（チセ）ハア…
I'm not outside?
（チセ）
外… じゃない？
You're a proper wolf this time.
（エリアス）
今度は ちゃんとオオカミだね
Um...
（チセ）あの…
I'm sorry if we were making too much noise.
もし 騒がしくて
我慢できなかったなら
ごめんなさい
I'll be more careful next time.
次は 気をつけます
Do you feel all right?
具合は悪くないですか？
Is there something that upset you?
何か気に入らないことが？
Elias?
エリアス？
Listening to your voices oddly
made me want to leave home.
（エリアス）
君たちの声を聞いてたら
何だか無性に家を離れたくて
I wanted Stella to go away.
ステラが早く帰ればいいと思った
１人になりたかったはずなんだけど
I thought I wanted to be alone,
but as soon as I knew you were chasing me, I felt better.
チセが追いかけてくるのが
分かったら 落ち着いた
でも…
And yet, I couldn't stop running.
走るのは やめられなくて
I don't get it.
よく分からない
（チセ）それは…
That's...
Why don't we go home and have tea?
帰って お茶にしませんか？
Elias must be more confused
about himself than he realizes.
（チセ）
エリアスは思った以上に
自分のことが分かってないんだ
I thought he was leaving me.
置いて… いかれると思った
Elias might have been the same way.
エリアスも
同じだったのかもしれない
それぐらい
思ってくれているんだと…
Can I allow myself the conceit of
thinking that's how much he thinks of me?
私は うぬぼれてもいいのかな
（母親）ご機嫌ね ステラ
You're in a good mood, Stella.
When are we going to Grandma's place next time?
今度は いつ
おばあちゃん家(ち)に行くの？
You're so impatient.
（母親）気が早いんだから
（母親）どうしたの？
What's wrong?
Nothing.
（ステラ）何でもない
（ドアが開く音）
（ルツ）ただいま！
I'm home!
Are they not home yet?
まだ帰ってないか
I'll take another look around.
（ルツ）もうひと回り 行ってくる
Our connection's being interrupted.
（ルツ）
つながりが邪魔されてる
Chise, where are you?
どこだ… チセ！
This might be bad.
（チセ）
これはマズいかもしれない
Elias.
エリアス… エリアス！
Elias!
Ruth.
ルツ！ ルツ！
Ruth!
He's going to eat me.
（チセ）
このまま食べられる？
He's going to consume me.
取り込まれる？
それは…
That's...
That's not good.
それはダメだ
I don't want that right now.
今は嫌だ！
飛んで！
Fly!
Over there!
そっちか！
（ルツ）どの影だ？
Which shadow?
Chise!
チセ！ あっ…
Are you looking for your master?
（春の女神）主(あるじ)を捜しているの？
Is she...
（ルツ）
これは…
You all made an offering of
raindrop fruits and branches to Mother.
あなたたちは お母様に
しずくの実と枝を
献上してくれましたね
In return, I'll lend you my flame.
お礼に
私の炎を貸してあげましょう
Thank you.
（ルツ）ありがとうございます
Next winter, when I become Mother,
次の冬 私がお母様になるときは
I hope you'll offer me
raindrop fruits and branches again.
また しずくの実と枝を下さいね
Chise!
（ルツ）チセ… チセ！
チセ！
Chise!
（チセ）ルツ？
Ruth...
（ルツ）
ああ 大丈夫だ　そばに来た
Yeah.
It's all right.
I'm here.
Thanks.
（チセ）ありがとう
Is it Elias?
（ルツ）エリアスなのか？
Yeah.
I think he had some kind of temper tantrum.
多分 かんしゃく…
みたいなものかな
（ルツ）かんしゃく？
A tantrum?
What did my mom tell me in these situations?
（チセ）
お母さんは 私に
どうやって言い聞かせてたっけ
エリアスが感じているのは 多分
What you're feeling is
probably what's called jealousy, Elias.
嫉妬… というものだと思います
A feeling of envy, of wondering why you're singled out.
“羨ましい”とか
“どうして私だけ”とか
But being jealous of someone— of something...
でも 誰かを…
何かを羨んでも 恨んだりしても
Being envious or resentful will only bring you misery.
苦しいままで どうにもならない
That's not something you're meant to throw at people.
それは 誰かに
ぶつけるものじゃないんです
It's something you have to deal with inside yourself.
自分の中で折り合いをつけなきゃ
（チセ）
そんなこと言って
Even though I'm the most envious of all.
自分が いちばん羨んでるくせに
Do you get it?
分かりますか？
Keep being selfish, and I'll have
to take matters into my own hands.
これ以上
わがままするなら
私にも考えがあります
ルツ！
Ruth.
（ルツ）チセ！
Chise!
There's no telling where this knife will land!
どこに刺さるか分かりませんよ！
Are you done now?
（チセ）気は済みましたか？
You really scared me.
（エリアス）すごくびっくりした
ごめん
Sorry.
ごめん…
It's okay.
いいんですよ
I'm not angry anymore.
もう怒ってないですから
（エリアス）怒ってはいたんだね
So you were angry.
A bit.
ちょっと
帰ったら たくさん話しましょう
Let's talk lots when we get home.
（エリアス）話す…
Talk?
（チセ）はい 一緒に
Yeah.
Together.
Stella taught me a lot today, too.
私も 今日はステラから
いろいろなことを
教えてもらったので
エリアスに聞いてもらえたら
うれしいです
I'd like for you to listen.
Let's stay up for a while in bed to talk,
それで 布団の中で
遅くまで おしゃべりをして
and fall asleep together tonight.
今夜は…
一緒に寝ましょうか
ほら 帰りましょう
Come on, let's go home.
Yeah.
They were like father and
daughter until just the other day.
（ルツ）
この間まで
父親と娘みたいだったのに
Now they're like mother and son.
今度は母親と子供みたいだ
I'm leaving now.
（チセ）いってきます
Yes?
（デイビッド）はい
H-Hello, is Angelica-san available?
こ… こんにちは
アンジェリカさんは…
Oh, nice to meet you.
はじめまして
俺はデイビッド･バーレイ
I'm David Burley. Angie's husband.
アンジーの夫です
Sorry, do you think you could wait for a bit?
（デイビッド）ごめんね
少しだけ待ってもらってもいい？
I don't mind.
（チセ）かまいません
Are you a mage, too, David-san?
デイビッドさんも
魔法使いなんですか？
I'm an ordinary human.
（デイビッド）俺は普通の人間
I'm lucky enough to both have a job,
運よく仕事があって
運よく家族とうまくいってる以外は
and have a good relationship with my family.
何の取り柄もないね
Other than that, I'm nothing special.
Dad, is there a visitor—
（アルシア）パパ！ お客さん…
（チセ）こんにちは
Hello.
（アルシア）こんにちは
フン！
Sorry, she's been a bit difficult lately.
ごめん
最近 ちょっと気難しくて
（チセ）いいえ
It's fine.
つい最近 似たような子を見たので
I just met a similar kid recently.
（ドアが開く音）
（アンジェリカ）デイビッド？
David, did you call me?
さっき呼んだ？
Ainsworth's not waking up?
エインズワースが目を覚まさない？
Not since the night of the 26th.
はい
26日の夜から ずっと…
Are you sleepy?
眠いですか？
O
n
e
,
t
w
o
,
w
h
e
r
d
o
y
u
b
l
o
m
?
U
n
d
e
r
t
h
e
w
i
n
d
o
w
h
e
r
t
h
e
c
h
i
l
d
r
e
n
s
l
e
p
,
w
h
i
t
e
f
l
o
w
e
r
s
o
n
t
h
e
n
i
g
h
t
o
f
a
p
l
e
m
o
n
.
T
h
r
e
,
f
o
u
r
,
w
h
e
r
d
o
y
u
b
l
o
m
?
O
n
t
h
e
f
r
a
m
e
o
f
M
o
t
h
e
r
'
s
m
i
r
o
,
a
l
i
t
l
e
b
l
u
e
f
l
o
w
e
r
b
l
o
m
s
.
You sang him a lullaby, and he fell asleep?!
子守歌を歌ったら寝ちゃった？
That thing did?
（アンジェリカ）アレが？
（チセ）アレが
That thing did.
（チセ）
自分でも
いろいろ調べてみたんですけど
I did some research, too, but I'm scared.
怖くて…
（ルツ:小声で）
そういう割に何回か試しただろ
You say that, but you tried a few things.
Don't tell Elias.
（チセ）エリアスには内緒(ないしょ)ね
If your magic compounded
with your song, that's magic itself.
歌に魔力が
上乗せされたんだとしたら
それは魔法そのものだよ
魔法…
Magic?
It doesn't normally happen unless you intend it,
普通は意図しないと
そんなことにはならないんだけど…
but that might be your talent, Chise.
もしかしたら
それが
チセの特技なのかもしれないね
My talent?
特技…
Then why am I bad at making sleeping aids?
（チセ）
私が睡眠薬を作るのが
苦手なのって…
Just a second.
ちょっと待ってな
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
アンジェリカさん
Angelica-san...
Thanks for the bracelet.
腕輪 ありがとうございます
I'd like to get you something next Christmas.
次のクリスマスには
お返しさせてください
楽しみにしてるよ
I look forward to it.
Want some more tea?
おかわりいる？
（チセ）あっ 大丈夫です
I'm good, thank—
あり…
Are you all right?
（デイビッド）大丈夫？
You should get some sleep
there if you're not feeling well.
具合が悪いなら そこで寝るといい
I heard you often push yourself too far.
よく むちゃをするんだって？
Thank you...
ありがとうございま…
ゴホッ ゴホッ
You can't really go to the hospital for it, right?
（デイビッド）
病院に行って
治るものでもないんだろう
You should take it easy.
無理はしないほうがいい
You know about that, too?
（チセ）それも知って…
There's someone who talks
about you like you're her own child.
自分の娘みたいに
君のことを
話す人がいるから
Angie hasn't changed ever since I met her.
アンジーはね
出会ったころと
全然 変わってないんだ
I'd been asking her out ever since I was a snotty brat.
俺が まだ 鼻たれのガキのころから
After more years than I can count on two hands,
両手じゃ足りない年数
ずっと口説いて 口説いて
she finally accepted.
ようやく オーケーもらえたんだよ
It was only after our daughter was born
娘が生まれて 最近ようやく
that I finally got a sense of
why she'd always turned me down.
彼女が首を振り続けた訳が
ちょっと分かった
I'm lucky.
俺は幸福だよ
独りで死ぬことを考えなくていい
I don't have to think about dying by myself.
でも アンジーは…
But Angie...
Our daughter...
俺たちの娘は
They have to continue sending
people off, and there's no end in sight.
終わりが どこか知ることもなく
誰かを見送り続けるんだ
It's painful to think about how many
days are left that we can laugh together.
笑い合える次の朝が
いつまで続くか
考えるのがつらいよ
But unlike me, if things pan
out for you, you can keep up.
でも 君は俺と違って
うまくいけば ついていける
だからさ
So let's live as long as we can
without stressing or forcing it.
俺たち 無理も むちゃも
なるべくしないでさ
You and I both.
できる限り 長生きしようよ
You're right.
（チセ）
そうですね…
There.
出来た
Yo, Chise, want some he—
（ルツ）おい チセ 手伝う…
Ah, you're awake.
（チセ）あ… 起きた
Was it the medicine or was it that?
（ルツ）
薬で起きたのか
あれで起きたのか…
Thank goodness, Elias.
よかった エリアス
I was so worried...
心配し…
（ルツ）
あ〜 うん　説明する
I'll explain.
We're going to get in trouble for coming out this far.
（グィー）
こんなに遠くまで来たら
怒られるよ
It's fine.
（ベァナ）大丈夫だよ
But kids aren't supposed to go this far. It's not safe.
（グィー）
でも 子供は危ないから 遠くは…
（ベァナ）わっ！ 何か光ってる！
Whoa, there's something shiny!
（グィー）あ… 待ってよ！
Ah, wait up!
（密猟者Ａ）フン！ 急ぐぞ
Let's hurry.
（リンデル）またぞろ密猟者か
Poachers, yet again.
Fools.
愚か者め
It's the caretaker!
（密猟者Ａ）管理者だ！
Surrender and return to the soil.
（リンデル）
観念して 土くれになってくれ
Nice to meet you, mister caretaker.
（カルタフィルス）
はじめまして 管理人さん
The moon witnessed our incomplete cycles.
tsuki wa miteita kaketeru bokura
We called to one another,
tagai wo yobiai nagara
Walking distant paths as we took the long way around.
toomawari de tooi michi wo aruita
Red and black attract one another...
hikiyoseau aka to kuro ga
Shadow and light chase after one another...
oikakeau yami to hikari ga
They're made of two related things
futatsu no tsuranaru mono de tsukurareteru yo
...everything in this world is.
konoyo no subete wa
Because you're here, I'm here.
anata ga iru kara watashi wa iru
Even apart, we're side by side.
hanaretemo soba ni iru
soba ni iru
We're side by side.
Everyone is continually searching
daremo ga jibun no mou hitotsu no
For one precious thing
kataware to iu taisetsu na mono
That they can call their other half.
sagashi tsudzuketeru yo
The wandering sorcerer, Joseph, is on the move.
（チセ）
動きだした漂流の魔術師ヨセフ
ヨセフの思惑が少女と魔法使いを
狂乱のロンドンへと導く
Joseph's scheming leads the girl
and the mage to frantic London.
Depending on price and terms, I'll take on your work.
（セス）
仕事ならば
金額と内容によっては
お受けいたしますよ